<?xml-model type="application/xml" href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/srophe/srophe-xQueries/master/Caesarea-Data-Entry-Phase2/testimonia-metadata-entry.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title level="m" xml:lang="en">Caesarea Maritima: A Collection of Testimonia</title>
            <sponsor>Vanderbilt University</sponsor>
            <principal>Joseph L. Rife</principal>
            <editor role="general"
               ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#jrife">Joseph L.
               Rife</editor>
            <editor role="general"
               ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#plieberman">Phillip I.
               Lieberman</editor>
            <editor role="general"
               ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#dmichelson">David A.
               Michelson</editor>
            <editor role="technical"
               ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#dmichelson">David A.
               Michelson</editor>
            <editor role="technical"
               ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#dschwartz">Daniel L.
               Schwartz</editor>
            <editor role="technical"
               ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#wpotter">William L.
               Potter</editor>
            <!-- Static metadata -->
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Testimonium identified by</resp>
               <name ref="jrife"/>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Testimonium transcribed by</resp>
               <name ref="dmichelson"/>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Testimonium translated by</resp>
               <name ref="dmichelson"/>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>TEI record created by</resp>
               <name ref="dmichelson"/>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Testimonium edited by</resp>
               <name ref=""/>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Editorial review by</resp>
               <name ref=""/>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Research assistance by</resp>
               <name ref=""/>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition n="1.0"/>
         </editionStmt>
         <!-- Static metadata -->
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Caesarea City and Port Exploration Project</authority>
            <!-- Static metadata -->
            <idno type="URI">513</idno>
            <!-- Just need numerical sequence -->
            <availability>
               <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0">
                  <p>Except for materials quoted from other sources, this entry is copyright DATE by
                     the contributors (Joseph L. Rife, et al.) and the Caesarea City and Port
                     Exploration Project. It is licensed under the Attribution 4.0 International (CC
                     BY 4.0) license.</p>
                  <p>Some texts quoted in this entry may be in the public domain in the United
                     States. No copyright is asserted for these quotations.</p>
                  <p>Some texts quoted in this entry may have copyright restrictions and are reused
                     under Section 107 of the Copyright Act of 1976 (Title 17 of the United States
                     Code) which permits “fair use” of copyrighted materials for purposes such as
                     criticism, comment, scholarship, and research. These texts remain under
                     copyright of their owners. No copyright infringement is intended.</p>
               </licence>
            </availability>
            <date/>
            <!-- add via post-processing -->
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title level="s" xml:lang="en">Caesarea-Maritima.org: A Digital Archive</title>
            <editor role="general"
               ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#jrife">Joseph L.
               Rife</editor>
            <editor role="general"
               ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#plieberman">Phillip I.
               Lieberman</editor>
            <editor role="general"
               ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#dmichelson">David A.
               Michelson</editor>
         </seriesStmt>
         <!-- Static metadata -->
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Born digital.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
         <!-- Static metadata -->
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Authors of testimonia are identified with URIs from The Virtual International
               Authority File, see <ref target="http://viaf.org">http://viaf.org</ref>. When
               multiple VIAF URIs exist, preference has been given to VIAF record linked to the
               Library of Congress authority file.</p>
            <p>Geographic locations are identified with URIs from Pleiades: A Gazetteer of Past
               Places, see <ref target="https://pleiades.stoa.org/docs"
                  >https://pleiades.stoa.org/docs</ref>.</p>
            <p>When possible, textual works have been cited using URNs according to the Distributed
               Text Services (DTS) system, see <ref
                  target="https://distributed-text-services.github.io/specifications"
                  >https://distributed-text-services.github.io/specifications</ref>. Additional
               identifiers have been adopted from the systems used by the Perseus Digital Library
                  (<ref target="http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/hopper"
                  >http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/hopper</ref>), Syriaca.org (<ref
                  target="http://syriaca.org">http://syriaca.org</ref>), and other relevant
               authority systems such as WorldCat Identities or OCLC numbers (<ref
                  target="https://www.worldcat.org">https://www.worldcat.org</ref>).</p>
            <p>Bibliographic items are identified by a unique Caesarea-Maritima.org URI, which is
               linked, when possible, to OCLC numbers and other identifiers.</p>
            <p>Dates have been encoded following the ISO 8601 standard, <ref
                  target="https://www.iso.org/iso-8601-date-and-time-format.html"
                  >https://www.iso.org/iso-8601-date-and-time-format.html</ref>, and the best
               practices established for the Srophé App, see <ref target="http://srophe.app"
                  >http://srophe.app</ref>.</p>
            <p>Languages have been encoded using ISO 639-1 (<ref
                  target="https://www.iso.org/standard/22109.html"
                  >https://www.iso.org/standard/22109.html</ref>), 639-2 (<ref
                  target="https://www.iso.org/standard/4767.html"
                  >https://www.iso.org/standard/4767.html</ref>), and 639-3 (<ref
                  target="https://www.iso.org/standard/39534.html"
                  >https://www.iso.org/standard/39534.html</ref>) codes, following best practices of
               the TEI guidelines, see <ref
                  target="https://www.tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/index.html"
                  >https://www.tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/index.html</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <!-- Static metadata -->
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="CM-Testimonia-Type">
               <desc>
                  <title>Caesarea-Maritima.org Testimonia Typology</title>: This typology defines
                  three subsets of testimonia employed by the project and is used in the
                     <gi>catRef</gi> below to further categorize a given testimonia record. </desc>
               <category xml:id="direct">
                  <catDesc>A "direct testimonium" contains a word or phrase that is a direct
                     reference to, or name for, the conceptual place Caeseara Maritima or its
                     environs in part or in whole. When a "direct testimonium" also contains
                     indirect references, the classification by type is nevertheless marked only as
                     "direct".</catDesc>
               </category>
               <category xml:id="indirect">
                  <catDesc>An "indirect testimonium" makes only an indirect reference to the
                     conceptual place Caeseara Maritima or its environs in part or in whole. This
                     indirect reference may take the form of a common noun or may be implied by
                     context.</catDesc>
               </category>
               <category xml:id="toponymic-epithet">
                  <catDesc>A "toponymic testimonium" contains a toponymic epithet related to the
                     conceptual place Caeseara Maritima or its environs. When a "direct testimonium"
                     also contain a "toponymic testimonium", the testimonium is marked as belonging
                     to both types. These two types do not always overlap and thus our data set also
                     includes "toponymic testimonia" which are not "direct testimonia".</catDesc>
               </category>
            </taxonomy>
            <taxonomy xml:id="CM-Language-Usage">
               <desc>The <title>Caesarea-Maritima.org Language Usage</title> taxonomy describes how
                  language codes applied to individual testimonia records should be interpreted.
                  These are used in the <att>ana</att> attributes in the elements found in the
                     <gi>langUsage</gi>.</desc>
               <category xml:id="caesarea-language-of-original">
                  <catDesc>The original language of a testimonia's composition, which may differ
                     from the linguistic expression recorded in the testimonia record. For example,
                     Severus of Antioch's Letters were originally composed in Greek but survive only
                     in an ancient Syriac translation. The testimonia representing the Syriac
                     version of Severus's Letters would use this category to record the original
                     language, Greek</catDesc>
               </category>
               <category xml:id="caesarea-language-of-testimonia">
                  <catDesc>The linguistic expression recorded in this particular testimonia record,
                     which may differ from the original language of composition. For example,
                     Severus of Antioch's Letters were originally composed in Greek but survive only
                     in an ancient Syriac translation. The testimonia representing the Syriac
                     version of Severus's Letters would use this category to record the language,
                     Syriac</catDesc>
               </category>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <abstract>
            <p/>
         </abstract>
         <creation>
            <title xml:lang="en" ref="" type="uniform" level="m">The Life of Severus</title>
            <ref>83-86</ref>
            <persName ref="http://viaf.org/viaf/13590360" role="author">Zachariah of
               Mytilene</persName>
            <origDate notBefore="510" notAfter="530">510s-520s</origDate>
            <origPlace ref="https://pleiades.stoa.org/places/520998">Constantinople</origPlace>
         </creation>
         <langUsage>
            <language ana="#caesarea-language-of-testimonia" ident="syr"/>
            <language ana="#caesarea-language-of-original" ident="grc"/>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <classCode scheme="https://distributed-text-services.github.io/specifications">
               <idno type="CTS-URN"/>
            </classCode>
            <catRef scheme="#CM-Testimonia-Type" target="#direct"/>
            <catRef scheme="#CM-NEAEH" target="#byzantine"/>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc status="draft"> </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <ab type="identifier">
            <idno type="URI"/>
         </ab>
         <desc type="abstract"/>
         <desc type="context">Zachariah of Mytilene's hagiographic account of the life of the early
            sixth-century miaphysite bishop, Severus, patriarch of Antioch, includes brief accounts
            of several other saints. In this testimonium, Zachariah describes a religious conversion
            episode from the late fifth century in which one of Severus' contemporaries, Anastasius
            of Edessa, travels via Caesarea Maritima in a manner which evokes the Apostle Peter's
            vision and journey to Caesarea as described in the New Testament (Acts 10). In this way,
            the author seems to blur together two figures, both of whom are called "the great
            Peter". The first figure is the New Testament Apostle Peter. The second figure is Peter
            the Iberian, a fifth-century miaphysite Christian leader and monastic founder whose
            monastery at Miaouma in Gaza became a spiritual home to Anastasius and other saints
            mentioned by Zachariah of Mytilene, The passage also emphasizes the intellectual and
            social connections between the law schools of Beirut and the miaphysite Christian
            communities of Caesarea and Gaza in this period.</desc>
         <ab type="edition">ܐܢܐ ܕܝܢ ܟܕ ܡܝܬܪ̈ܬܐ ܕܐܢܫ̈ܐ ܠܒܝ݀ܫܝ ܠܐܠܗܐ܆ ܕܦܛܪܘܣ ܗܘܰ ܕܡܢ ܐܝܟܪ݀ܝܐ܇ ܘܐܫܥܝܐ
            ܗܘܰ ܥܢܘܝܐ ܪܒܐ ܘܐܓܘܦܬܝܐ ܡܟܬܒ ܗܘܝܬ. ܬܖܝܗܘܢ̈ ܓܝܪ ܗܠܝܢ ܓܒܖܐ̈ ܟܕ ܒܦܠܣܛܝܢܐ ܥܡܪܝܢ ܗܘܘ: ܬܫܒܘܚܬܐ
            ܪܒܬܐ ܩܢܝܢ ܗܘܘ ܗܝ̣ܝܢ : ܠܘܬ ܟܠܗܘܢ ܟܪܝܣܛܝܢܐ̈܆ ܝܫ ܡܕܡ ܠܘܩܕܡ ܡܢ ܬܫܥܝܬܐ̈ ܕܕܐܝܟ ܗܠܝܢ ܆ ܐܢܣܛܘܣ
            ܗܘ ܕܡܢ ܐܘܪܗܝ : ܗܘ ܕܡܢ ܠܥܠ ܐܬܥܗܕܬ : ܕܫܘܐ ܠܬܕܡܘܪܬܐ ܘܠܟܬܒܐ . ܚܙܐ ܓܝܪ ܒܚܠܡܐ ܆ ܠܦܛܪܘܘܝ ܪܒܐ
            ܘܪܝܫ ܟܗܢܐ̈ ܕܡܪܢ ܝܫܘܥ ܡܫܝܚܐ ܇ ܗܘ ܕܐܦ ܠܝܫܡܐ ܕܪܝܫܐ ܕܫܠܝܚܐ̈ ܐܫܬܘܝ ܕܦܩܕ ܠܗ ܆ ܕܒܥܓܠ ܢܐܬܐ ܟܕ
            ܪܟܒ ܗܝ ܕܡܬܩܝ̇ܐ ܒܐܪܘܕܐ . ܗܘ ܕܝܢ ܟܕ ܩܡ ܆ ܚܙܘܐ ܥܡ ܦܘܘܕܢܐ ܐܘܕܥܢܝ . ܟܕ ܐܘܣܦ ܐܦ ܕܡܘܬܐ ܕܦܪܨܘܦܗ
            ܟܗܢܝܐ ܀ ܟܕ ܗܟܝܠ ܕܡܝܬ ]84[ ܡܢ ܗܠܝܢ ܕܐܫܬܥܝ: ܕܠܘ ܚܠܡܐ ܐܝܬܘܗܝ ܗܘ ܕܐܬܚܙܝ: ܐܠܐ ܓܠܝܢܐ ܐܠܗܝܐ :
            ܩܪܐ ܒܝܕ ܗܘ ܓܒܪܐ ܚܣܝܐ ܠܘܬ ܕܘܒܪܐ ܕܕܝܪܝܘܬܐ : ܠܐܢܣܛܘܣ ܬܡܝܗܐ ܆ ܐܡܪܬ ܠܗ ܠܓܒܪܐ ܪܒܐ ܚܙܝܬ ܫܪܝܪܐܝܬ
            . ܘܙܕܩ ܠܟ ܕܬܫܡܥ ܩܠܝܠܐܝܬ. ܗܕܐ ܓܝܪ ܪܡܙ ܗܘ ܓܠܝܢܐ. ܗܘ ܕܝܢ ܡܛܠ ܕܚܠܐ ܐܝܬ ܗܘܐ ܠܗ : ܕܗܝܕܝܢ ܠܗܝ
            ܗܘܦܪܟܝܐ ܡܕܒܪ ܗܘܐ܆ ܕܚܠ ܐܢܐ ܐܡܪ ܡܢ ܚܙܘܩܝܐ ܕܒܝܕ ܐܪܥܐ. ܘܝܬܝܪܐܝܬ ܒܥܐ ܗܘܝܬ ܕܪܘܚܐ ܕܓܪܒܝܐ ܬܗܘܐ
            ܠܝ܆ ܘܒܝܡܐ ܠܦܠܣܛܝܢܐ ܐܙܠ. ܡܛܠ ܕܝܢ ܕܝܘܡܬܐ̈ ܡܕܡ ܡܛܠܬܗ̇ ܕܗܕܐ ܟܬܪ: ܘܠܐ ܗܘܬ ܠܗ ܗܝ ܕܒܥܐ ܗܘܐ:
            ܘܐܝܬܘܗܝ ܗܘܐ ܒܩܘܛܦܐ ܠܚܙܘܐ ܗܘ ܕܚܙܐ ܐܥܗܕܬܗ ܕܨܒܐ ܕܒܝܕ ܐܪܥܐ ܡܠܘܢ ܢܪܗܛ ܠܘܬ ܗܘ ܣܓܝ ܩܘܠܣܐ̈: ܪܝܫ
            ܟܗܢܐ̈ ܘܥܒܕܗ ܕܐܠܗܐ ܪܒܐ ܘܦܪܘܩܢ ܝܫܘܥ ܡܫܝܚܐ. ܘܡܠܟܐ ܡܠܟܬܗ ܠܗܢܐ ܇ ܕܕܚܠ ܗܘܐ ܡܢ ܚܠܗ ܕܢܥܒܪ ܟܕ ܐܙܠ
            ܡܢ ܒܝܪܘܛܘܣ ܆ ܕܠܐ ܣܟ ܥܠ ܘܪ ܗܝ ܕܗܘ ܗܝܕܝܢ ܡܕܝܪ ܗܘܐ ܒܗ̇ ܒܐܝܡܡܐ ܢܥܒܪ . ܐܠܐ ܕܢܬܬܢܝܚ ܡܝܢ ܠܒܪ ܡܢ
            ܐ ܆ ܒܠܠܝܐ ܕܝܢ ܕܠܐ ܥܕܢܐ ܢܥܒܪܝܗ̇ ܠܨܘܪ . ܗܘ ܕܟܕ ܠܗܢܐ ܡܠܟܐ ܩܒܠ ܆ ܐ. ܐܝܬܝܗ. ܘܡܟܝܠ ܠܩܣܪܝܐ
            ܕܦܠܣܛܝܢܐ ܡܢܥ . ܐܠܗܐ ܗܟܝܠ ܗܘ ܕܠܗܢܐ ܩܪܐ ܠܘܬܗ ܒܝܕ ܗܘ ܓܒܪܐ ܚܣܝܐ ܐܥܒܕ܆ ܕܒܬܠܡܝܕܘܗܝ̈ ܕܪܒܐ ܦܛܪܘܣ
            ܢܦܓܥ܆ ]85[ ܘܡܢܗܘܢ ܢܐܠܦ ܕܐܝܟܐ ܡܕܝܪ ܆ ܥܕܡܐ ܕܠܘܬܗ ܕܗܘ ܐܙܠ. ܘܟܕ ܗܠܝܢ ܡܡܠܠ ܫܡܥ܆ ܕܟܕ ܩܠܝܠܐܝܬ
            ܐܬܦܩܕ ܠܟ ܕܬܐܬܐ܆ ܡܛܠ ܡܢܐ ܥܕܡܐ ܠܗܫܐ ܐܬܬܗܝܬ. ܘܒܬܪܟܢ ܟܕ ܠܘܬܗ ܐܬܐ ܘܒܢܣܝܢܐ ܩܒܠ ܡܝܬܖܬܐ̈ ܕܗܘ
            ܓܒܪܐ ܐܠܗܝܐ: ܘܬܘ݀ܢܝܐ ܕܡܛܠ ܫܡܥܗ܆ ܟܕ ܚܝ݀ܐ ܕܕܝܪܝܘܬܐ ܐܫܬܘܕܝ ܠܐܠܗܐ ܘܬܚܝܬ ܫܘܥܒܕܗ ܕܗܘ ܗܘܐ ܡܢ
            ܐܪܝܐ ܕܐܝܬ ܗܘܐ ܒܦܓܪܗ ܡܚܕܐ ܐܓܗܝ. ܗܘ ܕܡܬܩܪܐ ܟܘܪܗܢܐ ܟܗܢܝܐ܇ ܕܫܪܝ ܗܘܐ ܡܢ ܟܕܘ ܕܢܫܬܠܛ ܒܗ. ܟܕ ܗܕܐ
            ܐܬܝܕܥܬ ܒܒܝܪܘܛܘܣ ܠܐܠܝܫܥ ܬܡܝܗܐ ܠܗ ܟܕ ܠܗ ܠܛܢܢܐ ܕܢܐܬܐ ܥܒܕܬ܀ ܟܕ ܓܝܪ ܪܚܡ ܐܠܗܐ ܐܘܓܪܝܣ ܡܠܐ̈ ܡܛܠ
            ܚܝܐ̈ ܕܕܝܪܝܘܬܐ ܙܒܢܝܢ̈ ܣܓܝܐܢ̈ ܐܙܝܥ ܠܘܬܢ: ܡܣܟܐ ܗܘܐ ܕܝܢ ܕܢܨܘܕ ܠܟܠܢ ܐܘ ܠܣܘܓܐܢ ܟܕ ܦܫܝܛܐ ܐܝܬܘܗܝ
            ܗܘܐ ܒܙܢܘ݀ܗܝ. ܗܘ ܪܒܐ ܐܠܝܫܥ܆ ܠܬܘܗܝܐ ܕܐܟ ܗܢܐ ܠܐ ܟܬܪ. ܐܫܬܘܝ ܗܘܐ ܓܝܪ ܐܦ ܗܘ ܩܕܡ ܙܒܢܐ ܣܓܝܐܐ
            ܠܓܠܝܢܐ ܕܓܒܪܐ ܚܣܝܐ . ܕܦܩܕ ܠܗ ܒܠܠܝܐ ܩܘܡ ܘܡܙܡܘܪܐ ܕܚܡܫܝܢ ܙܡܪ ܠܐܠܗܐ . ܐܚܪܝܐܝܬ ܕܝܢ ܡܢ ܚܘܒܐ
            ܣܓܝܐܐ ܐܦ ܢܘܪܐ ܕܦܝܠܣܦܘܬܐ ܐܠܗܝܬܐ ܕܠܩܐ ܗܘܬ ܒܗ ܐܝܟܢܐ ܕܗܘ ܓܠܐ ܠܝ ܟܕ ܥܡܪ ܐܢܐ ܥܡܗ ܗܝܕܝܢ . ܐܝܟܢܐ
            ܕܟܕ ܠܐ ܣܝܒܪ ܗܢܐ ܠܫܠܗܒܝܬܐ ܕܩܪܝܬܐ ܐܠܗܝܬܐ ܠܘܬ [86] ܦܠܣܛܝܢܐ ܪܗܛ ܠܘܬܗ ܕܓܒܪܐ ܚܣܝܐ . ܘܬܚܝܬ
            ܫܘܥܒܕܗ ܗܘܐ ܟܕ ܢܝܪܐ ܕܦܝܠܣܦܘܬܐ ܫܩܠ.<note xml:lang="en" type="textual"/><note xml:lang="en"
               type="textual"/><note xml:lang="en" type="discussion"/><note xml:lang="en"
               type="corrigenda"/><idno type="CTS-URN"/><ref target=""/></ab>
         <ab type="translation">When recording the virtues of inspired men, of Peter from Iberia,
            and Esaias, the great Egyptian ascetic—while living in Palestine, these two were highly
            respected by all the Christians—I would like to begin with the story about Anastasius
            from Edessa, whom I have mentioned above as worthy of admiration and [worthy of] writing
            about. [Anastasius] saw, in a dream, the great Peter, the high priest of our Lord Jesus
            Christ, who is also called the Prince of apostles, ordering him to come quickly, riding
            a so-called post-horse (βέρηδος). When he woke up, he told me about the vision and the
            order, and even added a description of his holy face. When I then concluded, |84| from
            what was told, that what he had seen was not a dream but a divine revelation which,
            through this holy man, called the worthy Anastasius to monastic life, I said: “You have
            actually seen the great man, and you should obey at once! For this is the meaning of the
            revelation.” He, however, since he had an uncle who at the time was governing the
            province, said: “I am afraid to travel by land, and would prefer to wait for a northerly
            wind and go to Palestine by sea. ” Since, because of this, he was delayed for some days
            without getting what he waited for, and was becoming worried, I reminded him of the
            vision he had seen which urged him to hurry by land to the highly honoured high priest
            and servant of the great God and our Saviour Jesus Christ. And since, because of his
            uncle, he was afraid to pass through [Tyre] when coming from Beirut, I advised him not
            to pass through Tyre, where he [the uncle] was living at the time, at day-time, but to
            pause outside the city and then, in the middle of the night, pass through Tyre. He took
            this advice and acted accordingly, and eventually came to <placeName>Caesarea in
               Palestine</placeName>. And so God, who had called him by means of this holy man,
            arranged that he met some pupils of the great Peter |85| and learnt from them where he
            was living, so that he could go to him. When he was talking with them they said: “You
            were ordered to come quickly. Why are you so late?” And later, when he had joined him,
            and experienced the virtues of this divine man, and listened to the stories about [him],
            and had promised God monastic life, and become his subject, his body was immediately
            free from the leprosy, called the sacred disease, that was already beginning to get hold
            of him. When this became known to the worthy Elisa in Beirut, it made him want to go,
            too—for the God-loving Evagrius’ had exalted the monastic life many times, expecting to
            capture us all, or most of us. Being simple in his manners, the great Elisa was not
            delayed like this. He, too, had long ago been granted a revelation of the holy man, who
            ordered him to rise in the night and sing the Fiftieth Psalm to God. Eventually, then,
            strong love lit the fire of divine philosophy in him—as he revealed to me, for I was
            staying with him at the time—so that he, unable to endure the flame of the divine call,
            hurried to |86| Palestine, to the holy man, and became his subordinate, having accepted
            the yoke of philosophy..<note xml:lang="en" type="translation">Revised from
               {source}</note><note xml:lang="en" type="discussion"/><note xml:lang="en"
               type="corrigenda"/><idno type="CTS-URN"/><ref target=""/></ab>
         <listBibl>
            <head>Works Cited</head>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target="https://www.zotero.org/groups/2320447/items/HDQLHKW6"/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target="https://www.zotero.org/groups/2320447/items/6S6PPRW2"/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
         </listBibl>
         <listBibl>
            <head>Additional Bibliography</head>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
         </listBibl>
         <note type="related-texts"/>
         <note type="geography"/>
         <note type="prosopography"/>
         <note type="themes"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
