<?xml-model type="application/xml" href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/srophe/srophe-xQueries/master/Caesarea-Data-Entry-Phase2/testimonia-metadata-entry.css"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title level="m" xml:lang="en">Caesarea Maritima: A Collection of Testimonia</title>
            <sponsor>Vanderbilt University</sponsor>
            <principal>Joseph L. Rife</principal>
            <editor role="general" ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#jrife">Joseph L. Rife</editor>
            <editor role="general" ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#plieberman">Phillip I. Lieberman</editor>
            <editor role="general" ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#dmichelson">David A. Michelson</editor>
            <editor role="technical" ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#dmichelson">David A. Michelson</editor>
            <editor role="technical" ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#dschwartz">Daniel L. Schwartz</editor>
            <editor role="technical" ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#wpotter">William L. Potter</editor>
            <editor role="creator" ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#jrife">Joseph L. Rife</editor>
            <!-- Static metadata -->
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Testimonia identified by</resp>
               <name ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#jrife">Joseph L. Rife</name>
            </respStmt><!-- Static metadata -->
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition n="1.0"/>
         </editionStmt><!-- Static metadata -->
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Caesarea City and Port Exploration Project</authority><!-- Static metadata -->
            <idno type="URI">1</idno><!-- Just need numerical sequence -->
            <availability>
               <licence target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0">
                  <p>Except for materials quoted from other sources, this entry is copyright 2021 by the contributors (Joseph L. Rife, et al.) and the Caesarea City and Port Exploration Project. It is licensed under the Attribution 4.0 International (CC BY 4.0) license.</p> <p>Some texts quoted in this entry may be in the public domain in the United States. No copyright is asserted for these quotations.</p> <p>Some texts quoted in this entry may have copyright restrictions and are reused under Section 107 of the Copyright Act of 1976 (Title 17 of the United States Code) which permits “fair use” of copyrighted materials for purposes such as criticism, comment, scholarship, and research. These texts remain under copyright of their owners. No copyright infringement is intended.</p>
               </licence>
            </availability>
            <date/><!-- add via post-processing -->
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title level="s" xml:lang="en">Caesarea-Maritima.org: A Digital Archive</title>
            <editor role="general" ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#jrife">Joseph L. Rife</editor>
            <editor role="general" ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#plieberman">Phillip I. Lieberman</editor>
            <editor role="general" ref="https://caesarea-maritima.org/documentation/editors.xml#dmichelson">David A. Michelson</editor>
         </seriesStmt><!-- Static metadata -->
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Born digital.</p>
         </sourceDesc><!-- Static metadata -->
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>Authors of testimonia are identified with URIs from The Virtual International Authority File, see <ref target="http://viaf.org">http://viaf.org</ref>. When multiple VIAF URIs exist, preference has been given to VIAF record linked to the Library of Congress authority file.</p>
            <p>Geographic locations are identified with URIs from Pleiades: A Gazetteer of Past Places, see <ref target="https://pleiades.stoa.org/docs">https://pleiades.stoa.org/docs</ref>.</p>
            <p>When possible, textual works have been cited using URNs according to the Distributed Text Services (DTS) system, see <ref target="https://distributed-text-services.github.io/specifications">https://distributed-text-services.github.io/specifications</ref>. Additional identifiers have been adopted from the systems used by the Perseus Digital Library (<ref target="http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/hopper">http://www.perseus.tufts.edu/hopper</ref>), Syriaca.org (<ref target="http://syriaca.org">http://syriaca.org</ref>), and other relevant authority systems such as WorldCat Identities or OCLC numbers (<ref target="https://www.worldcat.org">https://www.worldcat.org</ref>).</p>
            <p>Bibliographic items are identified by a unique Caesarea-Maritima.org URI, which is linked, when possible, to OCLC numbers and other identifiers.</p>
            <p>Dates have been encoded following the ISO 8601 standard, <ref target="https://www.iso.org/iso-8601-date-and-time-format.html">https://www.iso.org/iso-8601-date-and-time-format.html</ref>, and the best practices established for the Srophé App, see <ref target="http://srophe.app">http://srophe.app</ref>.</p>
            <p>Languages have been encoded using ISO 639-1 (<ref target="https://www.iso.org/standard/22109.html">https://www.iso.org/standard/22109.html</ref>), 639-2 (<ref target="https://www.iso.org/standard/4767.html">https://www.iso.org/standard/4767.html</ref>), and 639-3 (<ref target="https://www.iso.org/standard/39534.html">https://www.iso.org/standard/39534.html</ref>) codes, following best practices of the TEI guidelines, see <ref target="https://www.tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/index.html">https://www.tei-c.org/release/doc/tei-p5-doc/en/html/index.html</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl><!-- Static metadata -->
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="CM-Testimonia-Type">
                <desc>
                <title>Caesarea-Maritima.org Testimonia Typology</title>: This typology defines three subsets of testimonia employed by the project and is used in the <gi>catRef</gi> below to further categorize a given testimonia record.
                </desc>
                <category xml:id="direct">
                    <catDesc>A "direct testimonium" contains a word or phrase that is a direct reference to, or name for, the conceptual place Caeseara Maritima or its environs in part or in whole. When a "direct testimonium" also contains indirect references, the classification by type is nevertheless marked only as "direct".</catDesc>
                </category>
                <category xml:id="indirect">
                    <catDesc>An "indirect testimonium" makes only an indirect reference to the conceptual place Caeseara Maritima or its environs in part or in whole. This indirect reference may take the form of a common noun or may be implied by context.</catDesc>
                </category>
                <category xml:id="toponymic-epithet">
                    <catDesc>A "toponymic testimonium" contains a toponymic epithet related to the conceptual place Caeseara Maritima or its environs. When a "direct testimonium" also contain a "toponymic testimonium", the testimonium is marked as belonging to both types. These two types do not always overlap and thus our data set also includes "toponymic testimonia" which are not "direct testimonia".</catDesc>
                </category> 
            </taxonomy>
            <taxonomy xml:id="CM-Language-Usage">
               <desc>The <title>Caesarea-Maritima.org Language Usage</title> taxonomy describes how language codes applied to individual testimonia records should be interpreted. These are used in the <att>ana</att> attributes in the elements found in the <gi>langUsage</gi>.</desc>
               <category xml:id="caesarea-language-of-original">
                  <catDesc>The original language of a testimonia's composition, which may differ from the linguistic expression recorded in the testimonia record. For example, Severus of Antioch's Letters were originally composed in Greek but survive only in an ancient Syriac translation. The testimonia representing the Syriac version of Severus's Letters would use this category to record the original language, Greek</catDesc>
               </category>
               <category xml:id="caesarea-language-of-testimonia">
                  <catDesc>The linguistic expression recorded in this particular testimonia record, which may differ from the original language of composition. For example, Severus of Antioch's Letters were originally composed in Greek but survive only in an ancient Syriac translation. The testimonia representing the Syriac version of Severus's Letters would use this category to record the language, Syriac</catDesc>
               </category>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <abstract>
            <p/>
         </abstract>
         <creation>
            <title xml:lang="en" ref="" type="uniform" level="m">Embassy to Gaius</title>
            <ref>37.299</ref>
            <persName ref="http://viaf.org/viaf/30151776786218011787" role="author">Philo</persName>
            <origDate>0040</origDate>
            <origPlace ref="https://pleiades.stoa.org/places/727070">Alexandria</origPlace>
         </creation>
         <langUsage>
            <language ana="#caesarea-language-of-testimonia" ident="grc"/>
            <language ana="#caesarea-language-of-original" ident="grc"/>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <classCode scheme="https://distributed-text-services.github.io/specifications">
               <idno type="CTS-URN"/>
            </classCode>
            <catRef scheme="#CM-Testimonia-Type" target="#indirect"/>
            <catRef scheme="#CM-NEAEH" target="#earlyRoman #herodian"/>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc status="draft">
         <change who="wpotter" when="">ADDED: testimonium ID, URNs, URLs to edition and translation,
            and Bibl URIs</change>
         <change who="jrife" when="">CREATED: testimonium</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <ab type="identifier">
            <idno type="URI"/>
         </ab>
         <desc type="abstract"/>
         <desc type="context">Philo was a Jewish philosopher and historian who flourished at
            Alexandria during the first generations of Roman provincial rule in Egypt. His
            voluminous writings are marked by their learning, variety, and fusion of Hellenistic
            philosophy with biblical exegesis, particularly his application of the critical strategy
            of allegoresis. In the year 40, he joined a diplomatic mission to the emperor Gaius
            (Caligula) as an advocate for the rights of the Alexandrian Jewish community after the
            major wave of riots with the resident Greeks. In his account of this “embassy”
            (πρεσβεία, <foreign>legatio</foreign>), Philo expresses to the emperor his concern over
            preserving the inviolability of the Temple in Jerusalem, especially against the
            introduction of foreign cult-images. Here he cites the affair of the golden shields that
            the governor Pontius Pilate had dedicated in Jerusalem during the reign of
            Tiberius.</desc>
         <ab type="edition">ἔχω δέ τι καὶ φιλοτίμημα αὐτοῦ προσδιηγήσασθαι, καίτοι μυρίων
            ἀπολελαυκὼς ὅτε ἔζη κακῶν· ἀλλὰ τἀληθὲς φίλον καὶ σοὶ τίμιον. Πιλᾶτος ἦν τῶν ὑπάρχων
            ἐπίτροπος ἀποδεδειγμένος τῆς Ἰουδαίας· οὗτος οὐκ ἐπὶ τιμῇ Τιβερίου μᾶλλον ἢ ἕνεκα τοῦ
            λυπῆσαι τὸ πλῆθος ἀνατίθησιν ἐν τοῖς κατὰ τὴν ἱερόπολιν Ἡρῴδου βασιλείοις ἐπιχρύσους
            ἀσπίδας μήτε μορφὴν ἐχούσας μήτε ἄλλο τι τῶν ἀπηγορευμένων, ἔξω τινὸς ἐπιγραφῆς
            ἀναγκαίας, ἣ δύο ταῦτα ἐμήνυε, τόν τε ἀναθέντα καὶ ὑπὲρ οὗ ἡ ἀνάθεσις.<note
               type="textual">Ed. Cohn and Wendland 1902</note><note type="textual"/><note
               type="discussion"/><note type="corrigenda"/><idno type="CTS-URN"/><ref
               target="https://scaife.perseus.org/reader/urn:cts:greekLit:tlg0018.tlg031.opp-grc1:299"
            /></ab>
         <ab type="translation">I can relate one example of (Tiberius’s) lust after honor, even
            though I have suffered thousands of hardships when he was alive; nevertheless, the truth
            is a dear thing, and worthy of your (sc. Gaius’s) respect. Pilate was appointed prefect
            over Judaea from among his lieutenants. This man, not so much to honor Tiberius as to
            vex the populace, dedicated gold-covered shields in the Palace of Herod in the holy
            city. These bore no shape nor anything other forbidden feature apart from the requisite
            inscription, which mentioned two things: the one who made the dedication, and the one
            for whom the dedication was made.<note type="translation">Trans. J. L. Rife with ref. to
               Yonge and Scholer 2013 [1855]</note><note type="discussion"/><note type="corrigenda"
               /><idno type="CTS-URN"/><ref target=""/></ab>
         <listBibl>
            <head>Works Cited</head>
            <bibl>
               <ptr
                  target="https://www.zotero.org/groups/2320447/caesarea-maritima/search/cohn/titleCreatorYear/items/2T3QPLC4/item-list"/>
               <citedRange unit="bk">37</citedRange>
               <citedRange unit="section">299</citedRange>
            </bibl>
            <bibl>
               <ptr
                  target="https://www.zotero.org/groups/2320447/caesarea-maritima/items/X6BZJ9UJ/library"/>
               <citedRange unit="p">784</citedRange>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
         </listBibl>
         <listBibl>
            <head>Additional Bibliography</head>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
            <bibl>
               <ptr target=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
               <citedRange unit=""/>
            </bibl>
         </listBibl>
         <note type="related-texts">
            <p>Philo, Embassy to Gaius 38.300-38.305</p>
         </note>
         <note type="geography">
            <p>Judaea</p>
            <p>Jerusalem</p>
         </note>
         <note type="prosopography">
            <p>Tiberius, emperor</p>
            <p>Pontius Pilate</p>
            <p>Herod I, king</p>
         </note>
         <note type="themes">
            <p>Roman History</p>
            <p>Jewish History</p>
            <p>Herodian History</p>
            <p>Government and Law</p>
            <p>Judaism</p>
            <p>Urban Topography</p>
            <p>Military</p>
         </note>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>